MOHAMMAD REZA KARIMI DASTJERDI

Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering. Université Laval 2325 Rue de l'Université, Québec, QC G1V 0A6, Canada Cell: +1 (418) 265 - 5772 • Email: mohammad.karimi-dastjerdi.1@ulaval.ca • Web Page

Overview

I am a specialist in computer vision and machine learning. My expertise is to develop learning-based solutions for problems at the intersection of computer vision and computer graphics. My skills span over:

- Lighting Estimation
- High Dynamic Range Imaging
- · Novel View Synthesis

- Image-based Lighting
- Generative Models

Education

PhD Candidate of Electrical Engineering, Université Laval, Canada	Sep. 2019-Present
Dissertation: Lighting Estimation and Capturing for Photo-realistic Virtual Object Insertion	
MSc in Culture Technology, KAIST, South Korea Thesis: Cinemagraph Generation from a Static Image with Generative Adversarial Networks	Sep. 2017–Jul. 2019
BSc in Computer Engineering, K.N.Toosi University of Technology, Iran	Sep. 2011–Sep. 2016

Publications

- M. Karimi Dastjerdi, F. Fortier-Chouinard, Y. Hold-Geoffroy, C. Demers, M, Hébert, N. Kalantari, J. Lalonde. PanDORA: Casual HDR Radiance Acquisition for Indoor Scenes. Under review. [Project page]
- J. Giroux, M. Karimi Dastjerdi, Y. Hold-Geoffroy, J. Vazquez-Corral, J. Lalonde. Towards a Perceptual Evaluation Framework for Lighting Estimation. IEEE / CVF Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition Conference (CVPR) 2024. [Project page]
- M. Karimi Dastjerdi, Y. Hold-Geoffroy, J. Eisenmann, J. Lalonde. EverLight: Indoor-Outdoor Editable HDR Lighting Estimation. International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV) 2023. [Project page]
- M. Karimi Dastjerdi, Y. Hold-Geoffroy, J. Eisenmann, S. Khodadadeh, J. Lalonde. Guided Co-Modulated GAN for 360° Field of View Extrapolation. IEEE International Conference on 3D Vision (3DV) 2022, Oral presentation. [Project page]
- P. Gera, M. Karimi Dastjerdi, C. Renaud, P. J. Narayanan, J. Lalonde. Casual Indoor HDR Radiance Capture from Omnidirectional Images. The British Machine Vision Conference (BMVC) 2022. Spotlight presentation. [Projet page]

Research Experience

Research Assistant, Computer Vision and Systems Laboratory, Université Laval

Sep. 2019-Present

- Proposing different methods based on Neural Radiance Fields (NeRF) and 360° cameras to capture HDR radiance of indoor scenes.
- Advised two graduate students and mentored multiple interns in their projects.

Research Intern, Adobe

May. 2022-Mar. 2023

- Proposed a lighting estimation method that works for both indoor and outdoor domains seamlessly and produces high dynamic range, high-resolution panoramas ready to use as HDRI in rendering engines.
- Introduced lighting comodulation in GANs, combining the flexibility and intuitiveness of parametric lighting models with the generative power of GANs, resulting in easily editable outputs.
- Adobe is currently integrating the proposed method for the Match Image feature of Adobe Substance 3D Stager.

Research Scientist Intern, Adobe

May. 2021-Nov. 2021

- Presented an end-to-end trainable pipeline based on GANs specifically tailored to the 360° FOV extrapolation.
- Introduced guided co-modulation mechanism in GANs to edit the content of the generated pixels without any GAN inversion.
- At the time, demonstrated state-of-the-art results both quantitatively and qualitatively.
- It is currently being integrated for face anonymization in Adobe Photoshop and Match Image in Adobe Substance 3D Stager.
- This work is featured at Adobe Max Sneaks 2022 as #ProjectBeyondTheSeen.

Patents

- M. Karimi Dastjerdi, Y. Hold-Geoffroy, S Bi, J. Eisenmann, J. Lalonde, Artificial Intelligence Techniques For Extrapolating HDR Panoramas From LDR Low FOV Images, Worldwide applications, Application no. 18238290 Pending.
- M. Karimi Dastjerdi, Y. Hold-Geoffroy, J. Eisenmann, V. Kim, J. Lalonde, Extrapolating Panoramas from Images using a Generative Model Worldwide applications, Application no. 18055716 Pending.
- J. Noh, H. Lee, B. Kim, G. Kim, J. Lelong, **M. Karimi Dastjerdi**, A. Kim, J. Lee, Image Processing Method and Device Therefor, US patent Patent no. 11893704. February 2024.

Honors and Awards

ICCV Doctoral Consortium (Oct. 2023)

Winner of Otis-Lalonde Scholarship (Mar. 2023)

Bourse en vision artificielle 2e et 3e cycle, Québec, Canada

Presentation Competition: First Place (Apr. 2022), Second Place (Apr. 2021)

Journées de la relève en intelligence et données, Québec, Canada

Machine Vision: Explorer League: First Place (Sep. 2015) Second Place (Nov. 2014) SharifCup Open Robotics Competition, Sharif University of Technology, Tehran, Iran

Professional Experiences

Chair, IEEE Young Professionals Affinity Group, IEEE Quebec Section (2021 - 2023)

Reviewer, SIGGRAPH ASIA (2024), ECCV (2024), CVPR (2024), IEEE TVCG (2024, 2023), 3DV (2021), CVPR workshop (2024), ICCV workshop (2021).

Student Committee Member, ICRoM 2014, 2016.

Technical Committee Member, The 2nd International Students Competition in Robotic, Amirkabir University of Technology, Tehran, Iran. Mar. 2016.

Technical Committee Member, The 1st KNTU Workshop on Robotics and Embedded Systems, Khazar University, Baku, Azerbaijan. Dec. 2015.

Computer skills

Programming languages Python, C++, and C

Machine Learning PyTorch, Keras, Tensorflow

Computer Graphics Blender, Maya, Unity3D

Language

English (Proficient) Persian (Native) Korean (Basic) French (Basic)

REFERENCES

Prof. Jean-François Lalonde

Full Professor

Electrical and Computer Engineering Department

Université Laval, Québec, CA Email: jflalonde@gel.ulaval.ca

Dr. Jonathan Eisenmann

Senior Manager - Tech Transfer

Creative Product

Adobe, San Francisco, USA

Email: eisenman@adobe.com

Dr. Yannick Hold-Geoffroy

Senior Research Scientist,

Adobe Research

Adobe, San Jose, USA

Email: holdgeof@adobe.com

Prof. Junyong Noh

Full Professor

Graduate School of Culture Technology

KAIST, Daejeon, South Korea

Email: junyongnoh@kaist.ac.kr